CORENTIN JABOT

♦ corentinjabot@gmail.com

I am a software developer with primary interests in Modern C++, language, API and library design. I have worked on a variety of domains and platforms and designed several applications with large user bases. I am also a member of the C++ Standardization Committee.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- \cdot Modern C++
- · Experience with Qt, boost, the clang front end, and other open-source projects.
- · Some knowledge of Python, Javascript, QML, WebAssembly, other programming languages.
- \cdot Development of library code, server & desktop applications, system & desktop integration (win32, cocoa, Linux).
- · API and network protocols design. Design of large systems, features and user experiences.
- · Working on complex problems and architectures from the ground-up. Autonomous, experienced with remote working.
- · Multi-platform build systems maintenance (notably CMake), CI, and deployment, installer frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

Mobsya/Freelance Senior Software Developer

2017 - Current

France, Switzerland

- · Software developer for Mobsya (Swiss non-profit) on the Thymio project an educational robot for schools.
- · Converted a set of research projects into a commercially viable offering.
- · Designed an asio-based application serving as a gateway between the robots (esp32, pic24) and various applications
- · Designed a multi-robots, multi clients architecture around zeroconf, flatbuffers. Maintained and improved Qt-based and JS-based applications and libraries.
- · Implemented new features in the firmware. Ported the build infrastructure to several public CI platforms, notably azure pipeline.

Freelance
Senior Software Developer
France

· Worked on "moolticute", a Qt-based desktop application to control a hardware-based password manager.

Ankama Studio

 $Senior\ Software\ Developer$

April 2009 - December 2016 Roubaix - Bordeaux, France

- · Main developer and maintainer of the updater solution used by Ankama to keep its games updated based on player feedback and internal team needs for over a million players on Windows/Mac/Linux.
- · The system included a centralized version manager to handle thousands of game versions, create and deploy patches, a client application to update the game, and a custom made and fully integrated installer framework. All these tools used C++ and the Qt framework, along with various scripting languages.
- · Managed the build systems, exploitation, support and some of the IT for these projects.

· Lectured college students on resources management in C++11 with the goal to give them an overview of C++11, and how to improve their code through the use of RAII and smart pointers.

Other works

- · Member of the C++ Standardization Committee since 2018 including the Unicode, Tooling and Reflection subgroups, as well as the French National Body to the C++ Standardization Committee.
- · Author of a few proposals for the C++ Standardization Committee.
- · Occasional contributor to the Qt open-source framework and other open-source libraries.
- · Occasional speaker at C++ conferences (notably CppCon in 2019)

EDUCATION

IUT Bordeaux 1

September 2006 - June 2008

2015 & 2016

 $Diplôme\ Universitaire\ de\ Technologie\ en\ Informatique\ (DUT).$ This 2-years technical degree in Computer Science covered a lot of topics and technologies.

INTERESTS

Beside programming, I enjoy hiking, cooking, movies. I also like to keep an eye on scientific discoveries, and I recently took on photography.

LANGUAGES

French and English.

LINKS

Github: https://github.com/cor3ntin?tab=repositories&type=source

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/corentin-jabot-190b9749/

Blog: https://cor3ntin.dev